# TALAL OWAIR

Tel: + 971 507837229 (UAE) Skype: TALAL.OWAIR Email: talalowair@live.com



#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Through a progressive 9 years career ranging from various entries level positions to management roles, I have demonstrated a strong commitment to our industry and to my employer's goals. I bring with me excellent technical knowledge of Food and Beverage, an understanding of a wide variety of outlets, indepth training from educational institutes and practical experiences, strong verbal and written communication skills, flexibility, creative thinking and a no surrender attitude.

My aim is to continue developing within a leading luxury property and to display a proven ability for encouraging, guiding, and motivating my teams toward the employer's goals and their personal successes. This is something I have done many times and was demonstrated in the consistent improvement of my departments' engagement scores. I enjoy the day-to-day work and engaging with guests and have a natural passion for food drink and the industry as a whole. As an accomplished team player, I strive to learn from others and always remain available and positive when assistance is required.

#### **Skills & Attributes**

- Fluent in English and native Arabic
- Over 22 years of experience in hospitality
- Hugely sales driven and skilled 'up seller'
- Effective management: delivering profit Centre profitability
- Loyal and dedicated employee
- A positive attitude even under pressure
- Vast food and beverage knowledge
- Highly professional and reliable individual
- Natural leader but also a team player
- Presentation Skills
- Relationship builder
- Emotional engagement
- Demonstrating solid time management, problem-solving skill and multitasking skills to excel within fastpaced, customer-facing environments
- Skilled 'people person' with a very customer service driven mindset

 Leadership skills of coaching, mentoring and motivation skills developing productive staff to propel restaurant success and achieve the highest level of customer service

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Mawal restaurant at Radisson blue hotel Abu Dhabi

November –present

- Managing team of 25 employees Team leaders, Waiters, Sommeliers and Bartenders
- Cultivated best practice guidelines by providing leadership and direction to employees
- Compiling reports for daily, weekly and monthly targets WIGs, Heartbeat, Post Mortem, KPIs, Appraisals, COM nominations, IDPs, Menu engineering, Forecasting
- Interviewing colleagues
- Managing cost by monitoring sales mix, wastage, breakages on weekly and monthly basis's
- Dealing with complaints in a professional manner with a successful outcome in a very fast paced and busy environment
- Vast profile guest knowledge and recognition
- In charge on maintaining safe environment for guests and colleagues
- In charge in the department's training with 2 of the team leaders by conducting training on daily basis and preparing a monthly training calendar and monthly quiz.
- Successfully participating in Hotsos
- Replying to all positive and negative survey on Revinat and being in touch with the guest directly
- Implementing and maintaining all the LQA standards during the service.
- Consistently achieving high result in the IFH audits with 100%, internal and external LQA audits with above 96%
- Develop and maintain an elegantly appointed environment, with superior staff, dedicated to an attentive, distinctive experience for all dining periods.
- Part of HAACP Team looking after all the F&B departments.
- Control usage of all food and beverage items and appropriate usage of equipment, tools and service equipment

# Al Dhafra group Restaurant Manager

#### December 2020-December 2021

- Managing team of 30 employees Team leaders, Waiters, Sommeliers and Bartenders
- Cultivated best practice guidelines by providing leadership and direction to employees
- Compiling reports for daily, weekly and monthly targets WIGs, Heartbeat, Post Mortem, KPIs, Appraisals, COM nominations, IDPs, Menu engineering, Forecasting
- Interviewing colleagues
- Managing cost by monitoring sales mix, wastage, breakages on weekly and monthly basis's
- Dealing with complaints in a professional manner with a successful outcome in a very fast paced and busy
  environment
- Vast profile guest knowledge and recognition
- In charge on maintaining safe environment for guests and colleagues
- In charge in the department's training with 2 of the team leaders by conducting training on daily basis and preparing a monthly training calendar and monthly quiz.
- Successfully participating in Hotsos
- Replying to all positive and negative survey on Revinat and being in touch with the guest directly
- Implementing and maintaining all the LQA standards during the service.

- Consistently achieving high result in the IFH audits with 100%, internal and external LQA audits with above 96%
- Develop and maintain an elegantly appointed environment, with superior staff, dedicated to an attentive, distinctive experience for all dining periods.

#### **Emirates Palace Hotel**

Septmber 2009 - August 2020

## Emirati Restaurant (Mezlai ) 2 years All Dining Restaurant (le Vendome)

- Managing team of 45 employees Team leaders, Waiters, Sommeliers and Bartenders
- Cultivated best practice guidelines by providing leadership and direction to employees
- Compiling reports for daily, weekly and monthly targets WIGs, Heartbeat, Post Mortem, KPIs, Appraisals, COM nominations, IDPs, Menu engineering, Forecasting
- Interviewing colleagues
- Managing cost by monitoring sales mix, wastage, breakages on weekly and monthly basis's
- Dealing with complaints in a professional manner with a successful outcome in a very fast paced and busy
  environment
- Vast profile guest knowledge and recognition
- In charge on maintaining safe environment for guests and colleagues
- In charge in the department's training with 2 of the team leaders by conducting training on daily basis and preparing a monthly training calendar and monthly quiz.
- Successfully participating in Hotsos
- Replying to all positive and negative survey on Revinat and being in touch with the guest directly
- Implementing and maintaining all the LQA standards during the service.
- Consistently achieving high result in the IFH audits with 100%, internal and external LQA audits with above 96%
- Develop and maintain an elegantly appointed environment, with superior staff, dedicated to an attentive, distinctive experience for all dining periods.
- Part of HAACP Team looking after all the F&B departments.
- Control usage of all food and beverage items and appropriate usage of equipment, tools and service
  equipment

### Mint restaurant Qatar (Italian Restaurant) Service Supervisor,

November 2005,2007-

- Supervise and coordinate in kitchen and dining area cleaning activities.
- Resolve Guest complaints regarding food service.
- Train workers in food preparation, and in service, sanitation, and safety procedures.
- Observe and evaluate workers and work procedures to ensure quality standards and service, and complete disciplinary write-ups.
- Assign duties, responsibilities, and work stations to employees in accordance with work requirements.
- Record production, operational, and personnel data on specified forms.
- Develop equipment maintenance schedules and arrange for repairs.

# Samira Mis Hotel Captain

Damascus, Syria June 2003 to 2005-

- Monitoring & ensuring F&B service operations are running smoothly.
- Organizing duty roster of service staff.
- Cost control, inventory, Training.
- Maintaining SOP for quality.
- Able to introduce innovative ideas for generating targeted sale.
- Guest interaction, menu planning.
- Addressing guest requirement and reaching to them.

### **Personal Details**

Nationality: Syrian
 Gender: Male
 Marital Status: married

# **Educational Background & Achievements**

Middle Education
 Basic Education Certificate
 Secondary School
 High School Certificate

Syrian University

• Fairmont Dubai Academy Certificate

Cost Control 2017

# **Computer Skills**

Bachelor of Hotel and Tourism Certificate

- Profession in computer programs
- Profession with Microsoft Office programs (Word-Excel-PowerPoint)
- Micros symphony
- Oasys & Gantnar (Time In & Out)
- FMC & ADACO
- Opera PMS
- Avero & Net View
- Hotsos , MSN & Oracle

#### **Achieved Awards**

- Employee of the month January 2014
- (Best Experimental Restaurant) 2015
- (Best Dining Experience) 2016
- Restaurant Team of The Year Short List 2018

#### Language

Arabic: Mother language.

• English: Fluent (Reading, Writing & Speaking).

### Reference

Nizar al Sadi

F&B Director

١

Emirates palace Hotel

• Mohamad Al Bloshi Asst F&B Director Emirates palace Hotel